<chapter id="ctip_reporting">
	<title>Build Result</title>
	<para>
		The projects registered in Hudson Server are marked in green (success) or red (failure) icons in the Hudson Server home page after the build is finished. 
		Let us check the details on the result of executing build.  
	</para>
	 <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>[project name]_report type project</para>
          <para>If the project name is clicked in Hudson server home page, Build History is shown at the bottom left. 
          The bulid list is shown under this item. To check the result of reporting the project built most recently, click time link. 
          Then five types of reporting results can be checked through the menu item on the left.</para>
          <orderedlist numeration="arabic" inheritnum="inherit">
			<listitem>
    			<para>Duplicate Code</para>
    			<para>Shows the list of duplicate source codes and displays the parts of duplicate codes in the source codes in orange so that they can be visually checked.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
    			<para>PMD Warnings</para>
    			<para>Analyzes potential problems by analyzing java source codes using PMD tool. 
    			Finds unused parameters, catch blocks not processed, and unnecessary objects generated. 
    			By displaying the parts that have potential bugs in the relevant source codes in orange so that they can be visually checked, 
    			and also shows the priority of the potential problems.</para>
			</listitem>		
			<listitem>
    			<para>Test Result</para>
    			<para>Shows the result of executing JUnit test case. 
    			Test case executing time, success or failure and the error message information can be checked through Hudson server.</para>
			</listitem>		
			<listitem>
    			<para>Coverage Report</para>
    			<para>Shows in figures how much the test case covers the original source codes, using Emma tool. 
    			Coverage for each class, method, block and line can be checked.</para>
			</listitem>	
			<listitem>
    			<para>Checkstyle Warnings</para>
    			<para>Naming and compliance with development standards of source codes can be checked using Checkstyle tool. 
    			The codes against Checkstyle among the source codes are displayed in orange so that they can be visually checked.</para>
			</listitem>	
		  </orderedlist>
		  <para>
		  	Related files and configuration of the reporting tool for quality check of each source code, and rule sets can be checked in [Anyframe installation folder]/ide/inspection folder in the Anyframe development environment based on Ant. 
		  	Thus, when there are changes, they should be reflected here. 
		  	
		  	They can be checked in [user home folder]/.anyframe/inspection folder in the Anyframe development environment based on Maven. 
		  </para>
		</listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>[project name]_build type project</para>
          <para>
          	If the relevant project name is clicked in the Hudson server home page, Workspace menu will be shown at the center right, 
          	and when it is clicked, the result of executing build can be checked on the page. 
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
        	<listitem>
          	<para>Maven build result</para>
          	<para>When the target folder under Workspace is clicked, the result file of packaging the project will be shown,  
          	and there is also the folder where the relevant packaging file is extracted. 
          	Thus, when the file is deployed in the development server using the web application server, 
          	the web application folder here should be recognized.  
          	</para>
        	</listitem>
        	<listitem>
          	<para>Ant build result</para>
          	<para>When dist folder is clicked under Workspace, the result file of packaging the project will be shown, 
          	and there is also the folder where the relevant packaging file is extracted.  
          	Thus, when the file is deployed in the development server using the web application server, 
          	the web application folder here should be recognized.</para>
        	</listitem>        	
          </itemizedlist>	
         </listitem>	
	</itemizedlist>
</chapter>