<chapter id="app_server_configurations_jeus">
	<title>JEUS</title>
	<para>
		Let us check the configuration we should be careful about when deploying sample applications where Anyframe plugins are installed in JEUS.
	</para>
	
	<section id="app_server_configurations_jeus_iam">
		<title>When IAM plugin is used</title>
		<itemizedlist>
   			<listitem>
   				<para>
   					6.0 : For compatibility with Spring Security library which is used in sample application 
   					created by IAM Plugin installation, the latest version of JEUS 6.0 package must be installed.
   				</para>
   			</listitem>
   		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	
	<section id="app_server_configurations_jeus_cxf">
		<title>When cxf plugin is used</title>
		<para>
			Apache CXF supports JDK 1.5 onwards, so JEUS server version should be 5 or 6, but in case of JEUS 5, 
			Apache CXF cannot be used because of JAXB library conflict. 
			Refer to TmaxSoft website for information on JEUS server and downloading.
    	</para>
     	<para>
			Yet, for a sample application generated by installing Plugin, 
			first refer to the notes for each plugin installed to check the measures for each WAS for using open sources.
     	</para>
     	<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					5.0 :Cannot use Apache CXF. Does not run, because of the difference between the versions of JAXB API, 
					IMPL and reference libraries deployed in JEUS server (JAXB 1.x), 
					and libraries deployed in web application implemented using Apache CXF (JAXB 2.x).
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					6.0 : Can be used in Apache CXF without additional setting. 
					Runs without problem, because the versions of JAXB API, IMPL and reference libraries deployed in JEUS server 
					(JAXB 2.x), and libraries deployed in web application implemented using Apache CXF, match. 
				</para>
				<para>
					However, Plugins provided in Anyframe are developed based on Jetty, so they basically use 8080 port. 
					Therefore, when using JEUS, open cxf-jaxws-servlet.xml file, and change the 'http://localhost:8080/...' 
					part to 'http://localhost:{JEUS use port}/...'. 
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
</chapter>