<chapter id="introduction_overview">
	<title>Overview</title>
	<para>
		Anyframe is a framework for development of open source applications and has the following characteristics.
	</para>
	
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<emphasis role="bold">Support for application development based on Plain Old Java Object (POJO)</emphasis>
				: It supports development of applications based on Plain Old Java Object (POJO) to reduce overlapping of basic design and detailed design due to frameworks or inconsistency between the model designed during development and the implemented model.
				
			</para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para>
				<emphasis role="bold">Handling of dependency through Dependency Injection</emphasis>
				: It minimizes the impact from the changes in implemented models by guiding interface-centered development and handling reference between objects and components through Dependency Injection. 
				
			</para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para>
				<emphasis role="bold">Implementation with developers focusing only on business logic</emphasis>
				: It can enable developers to focus only on business logic by allowing the codes of non-functional parts such as logging, transaction and exception handling to be separated from business function development. 
				
			</para>
		</listitem>
		
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<emphasis role="bold">Support for execution of useful patterns such as Singleton and Factory patterns</emphasis>
				: By supporting execution of Singleton and Factory patterns, etc. without direct implementation of them, it resolves the difficulty in directly implementing the patterns 
				useful to manage generation of instances during application development and to secure integrity of data.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<emphasis role="bold">Guide for MVC Model2 architecture</emphasis>
				: Presentation layers can be structurally developed by separating presentation logic and business logic when Java EE web applications are made based on Layered Architecture.
				
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	
	<para>
		Anyframe provides the following functions.
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<emphasis role="bold">Provision of plugin environment for integration of open sources and provision of best practices</emphasis>
				: It supports users to easily construct sample projects for the relevant project by properly selecting and installing wanted plugins. 
				For further details, please refer to <link linkend="plugins_structure">Plugin Structure</link>.
			</para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para>
				<emphasis role="bold">Provision of reusable technologically common services</emphasis>
				: It supports faster and more stable development by providing technologically common services reusable for important functions such as DB access, SQL processing, cache, and linkage with WAS. 
				
			</para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para>
				<emphasis role="bold">Declarative transaction handling</emphasis>
				: It provides the function of controlling transactions declaratively with simple setup without coding for separate transaction processing of JTA or JDBC data sources, independently from the Java EE environment.  
				
			</para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para>
				<emphasis role="bold">Provision of common functions necessary for development of web display</emphasis>
				: It supports easy and consistent development of the Mode12 type by making various parts commonly needed for application development such as control of flow on the screen, error handling, and unified authorization into a framework.
				
			</para>
		</listitem>
		
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<emphasis role="bold">Possibility to easily connect with various web client technologies</emphasis>
				: It provides a structure easily linked with various web client technologies such as Ajax, and a commercial X-internet tool, which are recently gaining much attention.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	
	<para>
		It also provides <emphasis role="bold">Anyframe IDE that includes Anyframe installation and project and code generation functions</emphasis> 
		to maximize convenience of developers when they execute projects based on Anyframe.
		The whole development process can be aided from installation of Anyframe to project structure, code generation and build execution
		through Anyframe IDE in the Command Line Interface or the Eclipse Plugin type.
		
	</para>
</chapter>