<section id="workingwithqueries_addingaquery">
	<title>Adding a Query</title>

	<para>
		There are two ways of adding Query to Query Mapping XML file.	
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<link linkend="workingwithqueries_addingaquery_querytesteditor">Setting through Query Test Editor</link>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<link linkend="workingwithqueries_addingaquery_queryeditor">Setting through Query Manager Editor</link>
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		For skilled users, setting Query at Query Manager Editor can be more convenient and faster, but there errors may occur
		as related items must be checked case by case and test also must be run.
		When using Query Test Editor, as it is needed to execute Query Test Editor every time Query is set, it can be troublesome sooner or later.
		Therefore, when using Anyframe Query Manager it is recommended to use Query
		Test Editor until setting Query statement in the beginning part of development, then 
		directly set it when it seems to no problem to copy and past the existing query after Query setting is set in pattern.	
	</para>

	<note>
		<title>Note : In an environment where Proxy server is used, it is needed to register Proxy  server to Eclipse to use Query Test Editor.	 </title>
	</note>

	<section id="workingwithqueries_addingaquery_querytesteditor">
		<title>Setting through Query Test Editor</title>

		<para>
			The benefit of setting Query statement through Query Test Editor is that it is possible to enter database/table/column information 
			with mouse through GUI, and that you can test the query statement you are setting  without closing Query Test Editor.		
		</para>

		<para>
			The process of setting Query statement by using  Query Test Editor is as the following.	
		</para>

		<note>
			<title>Note : Setting Query statement using Query Test Editor supports Dynamic Query statement in Named Parameter only.</title>
		</note>

		<orderedlist numeration="Arabic" inheritnum="inherit">
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Query Test Editor run</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>
					You can open Query Test Editor at <link linkend="gettingstarted_queryexplorerview_open">Query Explorer View</link> through
					Context Menu of Query Mapping XML file.					
				</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Running Add query at Context Menu
						</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata
									fileref="../image/WorkingWithQueries/addquery-editorstep1.png"
									align="center" />
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Query statement setting and test</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>
					To set Query, enter Query ID, Query statement,etc., and test the created Query statement and click Ctrl + S 
					or Save button of Eclipse toolbar, then add Query statement to Query Mapping XML file.				
				</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="../image/WorkingWithQueries/addquery-editorstep2.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>
					When assigning Query ID, it must be unique. Otherwise, Query Test
					Editor provides error message. When setting Query statement, set Query statement at "Query Statement"  text field.
					Double-click table name or column name of "Database Browser" on the right, then table name or column name is automatically entered
					to Query statement setting box.			
				</para>
				<para>
					When setting Dynamic Query, click "Get
					Parameters" button of "Input Parameter Information" to synchronize the variable of Query statement,
					In the case of Dynamic Query utilizing Velocity grammar, "Dynamic Query" is automatically checked.					
				</para>
				<para>
					When Query statement setting is completed, set proper test value and test Query statement.
					For test, click Test Query button or Ctrl + Enter.
					The test result is shown at <link linkend="gettingstarted_queryresultview">Query
						Results
						View</link>, and when there are multiple data, you can control the number of data by modifying the value of "Row Limit".				
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<emphasis role="bold">Checking created Query</emphasis>
				<para>
					Through Query Test Editor, Query Mapping XML is added to the Query statement and users can check it easily.					
				</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="../image/WorkingWithQueries/addquery-editorfinished.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="workingwithqueries_addingaquery_queryeditor">
		<title>Through Query Manager Editor</title>
		<para>
			Although you can't get the benefits of GUI environment, if you are a skilled user of if there is certain amount of Query statement accumulated,
			direct setting of Query statement through Query Manager Editor can enhance the efficiency of task.
			In addition, as Query Manager Editor provides various tags and attributes to the defined DTD of Query Mapping XML through Content Assist,
			it is easy to apply or improved the existing Query statement.			
		</para>
		<para>
			For details on Query Mapping XML structure, each tag and attribute, refer to Query Service in Anyframe manual.		
		</para>
	</section>
</section>
