<section id="workingwithqueries_openfilesbyusingcontextmenu">
	<title>Open Files by Using Context Menu</title>

	<para>
		Anyframe Query Manager provides function to easily find DAO-related Query statement or Query-related VO through Context Menu.		
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<link linkend="workingwithqueries_openfilesbyusingcontextmenu_contextDAO">Opening specific Query statement used at DAO</link>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<link linkend="workingwithqueries_openfilesbyusingcontextmenu_contextQuery">Opening DAO class where Query is used</link>
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>

	<section id="workingwithqueries_openfilesbyusingcontextmenu_contextDAO">
		<title>Opening specific Query statement used in DAO through Context Menu</title>

		<para>
			When you want to check the contents of a specific Query statement used in DAO, if there are too many Query Mapping XML files or Query statements,
			it can be difficult to find the Query statement. To solve this issue, Anyframe Query Manager provides directly opening the Query statement
			through Context Menu.
		</para>

		<para>
			How to use this function is as the following.	
			<orderedlist numeration="Arabic" inheritnum="inherit">
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Among Query statements used in DAO, double-click and highlight the Query ID that you want to open immediately,
						then select "Open Query in Query Manager
						Editor" on Context Menu.					
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata
								fileref="../image/WorkingWithQueries/openbycontext-openquerystep1.jpg"
								align="center" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						You can see that the Query ID you want to open immediately is opened through Query Manager Editor,
						and the Query ID is highlighted. 					
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata
								fileref="../image/WorkingWithQueries/openbycontext-openquerystep2.jpg"
								align="center" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="workingwithqueries_openfilesbyusingcontextmenu_contextQuery">
		<title>Opening DAO class where Query is used</title>

		<para>
			When trying to check in which DAO Query used in Query statement is used, it may be troublesome to search the DAO.
			To solve this issue, Anyframe Query Manager provides directly opening of the DAO through Context Menu.		
		</para>

		<para>
			How to utilize this function is as the following.
			<orderedlist numeration="Arabic" inheritnum="inherit">
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Double-click and highlight VO utilized in Query statement
						then select "Open Query in Java
						Editor" on Context Menu.			
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The Query ID you want to open immediately is opened through Java Editor.					
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata
								fileref="../image/WorkingWithQueries/openbycontext-openvostep2.jpg"
								align="center" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
</section>
