<section id="workingwithqueries_usingcontentassist">
	<title>Content Assist</title>

	<para>
		Anyframe Query Manager enables more convenient and faster edition and utilization of Query statement by providing Content Assist function.
		Users can utilize functions provided by Content Assist of Anyframe Query Manager through keyboard shortcut key(default: Ctrl+Space)
		like other Content Assist.		
	</para>

	<section id="workingwithqueries_usingcontentassist_preference">
		<title>Content Assist environment setting</title>

		<para>
			You can set Content Assist at "Java > Editor >
			Content Assist > Advanced" of Eclipse Preferences
			and decide whether Content Assist of Anyframe Query Manager will be called by shortcut key.		
		</para>

		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata
					fileref="../image/WorkingWithQueries/contentassist-preferences.png"
					align="center" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>

	<section id="workingwithqueries_usingcontentassist_queryproposal">
		<title>Query Proposal of Content Assist</title>

		<para>
			For DAO(when either utilizing IQueryService or inheriting AbstractDAO) of Anyframe at Eclipse Java Editor,
			Content Assist shows the candidate list for the Query ID. This function is provided when Content Assist is called through keyboard shortcut key
			at Query input part (" " part in String type) which Query service method gets as a parameter.		
		</para>

		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata
					fileref="../image/WorkingWithQueries/contentassist-queryproposal.png"
					align="center" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>

		<note>
			<title>Note:when searching/entering candidate list for Query ID through Content Assist</title>
			<para>
				When the method is create(), findByPk(),
				findListWithPaging(), update(), remove(), etc. inheriting from AbstractDAO,
				the only Query statement that follow prefix and suffix rules set in <link linkend="gettingstarted_preferences">Preferences</link>
				of Anyframe Query Manager through Content Assist is searched.		
			</para>
		</note>
	</section>

	<section id="workingwithqueries_usingcontentassist_editing">
		<title>Query Mapping XML edition support of Content Assist  
		</title>

		<para>
			When editing Query at Source tab of Query Manager Editor at Anyframe Query Manager,
			candidate list for Query Mapping XML tag and attribute is shown.			
		</para>

	</section>

	<section id="workingwithqueries_usingcontentassist_navigation">
		<title>Providing navigation between Query and Java code. </title>

		<para>
			Navigation between Query and Java code is possible, and which supports the following cases.			
		</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Moving from Query Manager Editor to Result Class(VO) (Context Menu:
					Open Class in Java Editor)
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Moving from Query Service DAO to Query (Context Menu: Open Query in
					Query Manager Editor)
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
</section>